<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Library on rbxmk</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/categories/library/</link><description>Recent content in Library on rbxmk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2022 Anaminus</copyright><atom:link href="https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/categories/library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>base</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/</guid><description>The base library is an abridgment of the Lua 5.1 standard library . It is loaded directly into the global environment.
Overview # Item Kind Description _G Field The global environment. _VERSION Field The current version of Lua. assert Function Tests a condition. error Function Throws an error. getmetatable Function Gets the metatable of a value. ipairs Function Returns an iterator over an array. next Function Gets the next field in a table.</description></item><item><title>program</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/program/</guid><description>The program library is loaded directly into the global environment. It contains values related to the compiled executable.
Overview # Item Kind Description _RBXMK_VERSION Field The current version of rbxmk. Fields # _RBXMK_VERSION # _RBXMK_VERSION: string [readonly]
The _RBXMK_VERSION global variable is defined as a string containing the current version of rbxmk, formatted according to semantic versioning .</description></item><item><title>rbxmk</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxmk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxmk/</guid><description>The rbxmk library contains functions related to the rbxmk engine.
Overview # Item Kind Description globalAttrConfig Field Get or set the global AttrConfig. globalDesc Field Get or set the global descriptor. decodeFormat Function Deserialize data from bytes. encodeFormat Function Serialize data into bytes. formatCanDecode Function Check whether a format decodes into a type. get Function Gets the property of an instance. loadFile Function Load the content of a file as a function.</description></item><item><title>roblox</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/roblox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/roblox/</guid><description>The Roblox library contains an environment similar to the Roblox Lua API. It is included directly into the global environment.
Overview # Item Kind Description typeof Function Gets the internal type of a userdata. Functions # typeof # typeof(value: any): string
The typeof function returns the type of a value. For userdata, the internal value is returned. Other Lua values return the same as the type function.</description></item><item><title>clipboard</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/clipboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/clipboard/</guid><description>The clipboard library provides an interface to the operating system&amp;rsquo;s clipboard.
The clipboard is currently available only on Windows. Other operating systems return no data.
Overview # Item Kind Description read Function Gets data from the clipboard in one of a number of formats. write Function Sets data to the clipboard in a number of formats. Functions # read # clipboard.read(...: FormatSelector): (value: any?)
The read function gets a value from the clipboard according to one of the given formats .</description></item><item><title>fs</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/fs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/fs/</guid><description>The fs library provides an interface to the file system.
Overview # Item Kind Description dir Function Gets a list of files in a directory. mkdir Function Makes a new directory. read Function Reads data from a file in a certain format. remove Function Removes a file or directory. rename Function Moves a file or directory. stat Function Gets metadata about a file. write Function Writes data to a file in a certain format.</description></item><item><title>http</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/http/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/http/</guid><description>The http library provides an interface to resources on the network via HTTP.
Overview # Item Kind Description request Function Begins an HTTP request. Functions # request # http.request(options: HttpOptions): (req: HttpRequest)
The request function begins a request with the specified options . Returns a request object that may be resolved or canceled . Throws an error if the request could not be started.</description></item><item><title>json</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/json/</guid><description>The json library provides functions for handling JSON data.
Overview # Item Kind Description diff Function Get difference between two JSON values. fromString Function Converts a string to a JSON value. patch Function Tranforms a JSON value according to a patch. string Function no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/json:Fields/string/Summary&amp;rdquo; Functions # diff # json.diff(prev: JsonValue, next: JsonValue): {JsonPatch}?
The diff function returns a patch that represents the transformation of prev to next.</description></item><item><title>math</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/math/</guid><description>The math library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s
math library :
Overview # Item Kind Description clamp Function Returns a number clamped between a minimum and maximum. log Function Includes optional base argument. round Function Rounds a number to the nearest integer. sign Function Returns the sign of a number. Functions # clamp # math.clamp(x: number, min: number, max: number): number</description></item><item><title>os</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/os/</guid><description>The os library is an extension to the standard library.
Overview # Item Kind Description getenv Function Gets an environment variable. Functions # getenv # os.getenv(name: string?): string?|{[string]: string}
The getenv function returns the value of the name environment variable, or nil if no such value is defined. If name is not specified, then a table of environment variable names mapped to values is returned.</description></item><item><title>path</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/path/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/path/</guid><description>The path library provides functions that handle file paths.
Overview # Item Kind Description clean Function Cleans up a file path. expand Function Expands predefined file path variables. join Function Joins a number of file paths together. rel Function Produces a relative path. split Function Splits a file path into its components. Functions # clean # path.clean(path: string): string
The clean function returns the shortest path equivalent to path. Separators are replaced with the OS-specific path separator.</description></item><item><title>rbxassetid</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxassetid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxassetid/</guid><description>The rbxassetid library provides an interface to assets on the Roblox website.
Overview # Item Kind Description read Function Reads data from a rbxassetid in a certain format. write Function Writes data to a rbxassetid in a certain format. Functions # read # rbxassetid.read(options: RbxAssetOptions): (value: any)
The read function downloads an asset according to the given options . Returns the content of the asset corresponding to AssetId, decoded according to Format.</description></item><item><title>string</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/string/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/string/</guid><description>The string library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s string library .
Overview # Item Kind Description split Function Splits a string into a list of substrings. Functions # split # string.split(s: string, sep: string? = &amp;quot;,&amp;quot;): {string}
The split function splits s into substrings separated by sep.
If sep is nil, or if sep is not nil but not in s, then split returns a table with s as its only element.</description></item><item><title>sym</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/sym/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/sym/</guid><description>The sym library contains Symbol values. A symbol is a unique identifier that can be used to access certain metadata fields of an Instance .
An instance can be indexed with a symbol to get a metadata value in the same way it can be indexed with a string to get a property value:
local instance = Instance.new(&amp;#34;Workspace&amp;#34;) instance[sym.IsService] = true print(instance[sym.IsService]) --&amp;gt; true Overview # Item Kind Description AttrConfig Field Gets the inherited AttrConfig of an instance.</description></item><item><title>table</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/table/</guid><description>The table library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s table library .
Overview # Item Kind Description clear Function Removes all entries from a table. create Function Creates a new table with a preallocated capacity. find Function Find the index of a value in a table. move Function Copies the entries in a table. pack Function Packs arguments into a table. unpack Function Unpacks a table into arguments.</description></item></channel></rss>