<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rbxmk - A tool for processing Roblox files on rbxmk</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/</link><description>Recent content in rbxmk - A tool for processing Roblox files on rbxmk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2022 Anaminus</copyright><atom:link href="https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extensions</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/extensions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/extensions/</guid><description> Stub # Not yet implemented.</description></item><item><title>Instances</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/instances/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/instances/</guid><description>A major difference between Roblox and rbxmk is what an instance represents. In Roblox, an instance is a live object that acts and reacts. In rbxmk, an instance represents data, and only data.
Consider the RBXL file format. Files of this format contain information used to reconstruct the instances that make up a place or model. Such files are static: they contain only data, but are difficult to manipulate in-place. Instances in rbxmk are like this, except that they are also interactive: the user can freely modify data and move it around.</description></item><item><title>Configs</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/configs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/configs/</guid><description>Not yet implemented. The following configs are defined by rbxmk:
Config Description ClassName Set the field of Instances that determines the class of the instance. IndexChildren Set whether instances have child indexing behavior. ClassName # TODO
IndexChildren # TODO</description></item><item><title>Behaviors</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/behaviors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/descriptors/behaviors/</guid><description>Not yet implemented. This page lists and describes the available behavior descriptors.
Each behavior has a corresponding class and field. That is, when the combination of class and field has no definition, that behavior is used as the default. A behavior can be explicitly unset by setting the behavior to an empty string.
Basic # Behavior Description Instance.ClearAllChildren Returns ClearAllChildren method. Instance.Clone Returns Clone method. Instance.Destroy Returns Destroy method. Instance.FindFirstAncestor Returns FindFirstAncestor method.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/configuration/</guid><description>Not yet implemented. Stub #</description></item><item><title>Permissions system</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/permissions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/permissions/</guid><description>Not yet implemented. Stub #</description></item><item><title>Automation</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/automation/</guid><description>Not yet implemented. Stub #</description></item><item><title>rbxmk vs Remodel</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/remodel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/overview/remodel/</guid><description>Remodel is a tool similar to rbxmk. It also runs Lua scripts, and has its own Lua API. This page lists the Lua APIs provided by Remodel, and their equivalents in rbxmk.
Descriptors # Remodel has API descriptors built-in, whereas descriptors in rbxmk must be specified by the user.
To fetch the latest descriptors provided by Roblox, the --desc-latest flag can be passed. Additionally, the dump-patch file can be applied afterwards to further improve compatibility.</description></item><item><title>Enum</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxmk/enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxmk/enum/</guid><description>The Enum field is a collection of Enum values defined by rbxmk.
Item Kind Description DescActionElement Field no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Types/DescAction:Enums/DescActionElement/Summary&amp;rdquo; DescActionType Field no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Types/DescAction:Enums/DescActionType/Summary&amp;rdquo; Fields # DescActionElement # no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Types/DescAction:Enums/DescActionElement/Description&amp;rdquo;
Enum item Value Description Class 1 Property 2 Function 3 Event 4 Callback 5 Enum 6 EnumItem 7 DescActionType # no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Types/DescAction:Enums/DescActionType/Description&amp;rdquo;
Enum item Value Description Remove -1 Change 0 Add 1</description></item><item><title>math</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/math/</guid><description>The math library contains common mathematical functions and variables.
Item Kind Description huge Field The value &amp;gt;= any other numerical value. pi Field The value of π. abs Function Returns the absolute value of x. acos Function Returns the arc cosine of x. asin Function Returns the arc sine of x. atan Function Returns the arc tangent of x. atan2 Function Returns the arc tangent of y/ x. ceil Function Returns the smallest integer &amp;gt;= x.</description></item><item><title>os</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/os/</guid><description>The os library contains functions related to the operating system.
Item Kind Description clock Function Returns the CPU time. date Function Returns the current time.
Returns the time as a table.
Returns the time as a formatted string. difftime Function Returns the difference between two times. time Function Returns a numeric time. Functions # clock # os.clock(): number
The clock function returns, approximately, the seconds of CPU time used by the program.</description></item><item><title>program</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/program/</guid><description>The program library is loaded directly into the global environment. It contains values related to the compiled executable.
Item Kind Description _RBXMK_VERSION Field The current version of rbxmk. Fields # _RBXMK_VERSION # _RBXMK_VERSION: string [readonly]
The _RBXMK_VERSION global variable is defined as a string containing the current version of rbxmk, formatted according to semantic versioning.</description></item><item><title>string</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/string/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/string/</guid><description>The string library provides functions for string manipulation.
All strings have a metatable with the __index field set to this library. This allows functions to be called as methods on strings:
s:byte(...) -- Equivalent to: string.byte(s, ...) Item Kind Description byte Function Gets the bytes of a string subset. char Function Converts bytes to a string. find Function Finds the indices of a pattern. format Function Formats values as a string.</description></item><item><title>table</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/table/</guid><description>The table library provides functions for manipulating tables.
Most functions assume that the table is an array, where &amp;ldquo;length&amp;rdquo; refers to the result of the # operator.
Item Kind Description concat Function Concatenates each element as a string. insert Function Inserts an element.
Appends an element. maxn Function Returns the largest positive numerical index. remove Function Removes an element. sort Function Sorts elements. Functions # concat # table.concat(t: {string | number}, sep: string?</description></item><item><title>roblox</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/roblox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/roblox/</guid><description>The Roblox library contains an environment similar to the Roblox Lua API. It is included directly into the global environment.
Item Kind Description typeof Function Gets the internal type of a userdata. Functions # typeof # typeof(value: any): string
The typeof function returns the type of a value. For userdata, the internal value is returned. Other Lua values return the same as the type function.</description></item><item><title>clipboard</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/clipboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/clipboard/</guid><description>The clipboard library provides an interface to the operating system&amp;rsquo;s clipboard.
The clipboard is currently available only on Windows. Other operating systems return no data.
Item Kind Description read Function Gets data from the clipboard in one of a number of formats. write Function Sets data to the clipboard in a number of formats. Functions # read # clipboard.read(...: FormatSelector): (value: any?)
The read function gets a value from the clipboard according to one of the given formats.</description></item><item><title>debug</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/debug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/debug/</guid><description>no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/debug:Description&amp;rdquo;
Item Kind Description cachelen Function no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/debug:Fields/cachelen/Summary&amp;rdquo; gc Function no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/debug:Fields/gc/Summary&amp;rdquo; Functions # cachelen # debug.cachelen(): int
no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/debug:Fields/cachelen/Description&amp;rdquo;
gc # debug.gc()
no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/debug:Fields/gc/Description&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>fs</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/fs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/fs/</guid><description>The fs library provides an interface to the file system.
Item Kind Description dir Function Gets a list of files in a directory. mkdir Function Makes a new directory. read Function Reads data from a file in a certain format. remove Function Removes a file or directory. rename Function Moves a file or directory. stat Function Gets metadata about a file. write Function Writes data to a file in a certain format.</description></item><item><title>http</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/http/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/http/</guid><description>The http library provides an interface to resources on the network via HTTP.
Item Kind Description request Function Begins an HTTP request. Functions # request # http.request(options: HttpOptions): (req: HttpRequest)
The request function begins a request with the specified options. Returns a request object that may be resolved or canceled. Throws an error if the request could not be started.</description></item><item><title>json</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/json/</guid><description>The json library provides functions for handling JSON data.
Item Kind Description diff Function Get difference between two JSON values. fromString Function Converts a string to a JSON value. patch Function Tranforms a JSON value according to a patch. string Function no content for topic &amp;ldquo;Libraries/json:Fields/string/Summary&amp;rdquo; Functions # diff # json.diff(prev: JsonValue, next: JsonValue): {JsonPatch}?
The diff function returns a patch that represents the transformation of prev to next. This patch can be applied with json.</description></item><item><title>math</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/math/</guid><description>The math library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s
math library:
Item Kind Description clamp Function Returns a number clamped between a minimum and maximum. log Function Includes optional base argument. round Function Rounds a number to the nearest integer. sign Function Returns the sign of a number. Functions # clamp # math.clamp(x: number, min: number, max: number): number
The clamp function returns x clamped so that it is not less than min or greater than max.</description></item><item><title>os</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/os/</guid><description>The os library is an extension to the standard library.
Item Kind Description getenv Function Gets an environment variable. Functions # getenv # os.getenv(name: string?): string?|{[string]: string}
The getenv function returns the value of the name environment variable, or nil if no such value is defined. If name is not specified, then a table of environment variable names mapped to values is returned.</description></item><item><title>path</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/path/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/path/</guid><description>The path library provides functions that handle file paths.
Item Kind Description clean Function Cleans up a file path. expand Function Expands predefined file path variables. join Function Joins a number of file paths together. split Function Splits a file path into its components. Functions # clean # path.clean(path: string): string
The clean function returns the shortest path equivalent to path. Separators are replaced with the OS-specific path separator.
expand # path.</description></item><item><title>rbxassetid</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxassetid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/rbxassetid/</guid><description>The rbxassetid library provides an interface to assets on the Roblox website.
Item Kind Description read Function Reads data from a rbxassetid in a certain format. write Function Writes data to a rbxassetid in a certain format. Functions # read # rbxassetid.read(options: RbxAssetOptions): (value: any)
The read function downloads an asset according to the given options. Returns the content of the asset corresponding to AssetId, decoded according to Format.
Throws an error if a problem occurred while downloading the asset.</description></item><item><title>string</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/string/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/string/</guid><description>The string library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s string library.
Item Kind Description split Function Splits a string into a list of substrings. Functions # split # string.split(s: string, sep: string? = &amp;quot;,&amp;quot;): {string}
The split function splits s into substrings separated by sep.
If sep is nil, or if sep is not nil but not in s, then split returns a table with s as its only element.</description></item><item><title>sym</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/sym/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/sym/</guid><description>The sym library contains Symbol values. A symbol is a unique identifier that can be used to access certain metadata fields of an Instance.
An instance can be indexed with a symbol to get a metadata value in the same way it can be indexed with a string to get a property value:
local instance = Instance.new(&amp;#34;Workspace&amp;#34;) instance[sym.IsService] = true print(instance[sym.IsService]) --&amp;gt; true Item Kind Description AttrConfig Field Gets the inherited AttrConfig of an</description></item><item><title>table</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/table/</guid><description>The table library is an extension to the standard library that includes the same additions to Roblox&amp;rsquo;s table library.
Item Kind Description clear Function Removes all entries from a table. create Function Creates a new table with a preallocated capacity. find Function Find the index of a value in a table. move Function Copies the entries in a table. pack Function Packs arguments into a table. unpack Function Unpacks a table into arguments.</description></item><item><title>Compiling from source</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/installation/compiling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/installation/compiling/</guid><description>This document contains information for compiling and installing rbxmk.
rbxmk is written in Go. For development, it is recommend to be familiar with the go command. Basic installation # Instead of using prebuilt releases, rbxmk can be installed manually.
Install Go Install Git Using a shell with Git (such as Git Bash), run the following command: go install github.com/anaminus/rbxmk/rbxmk@latest If you installed Go correctly, this will install the latest version of rbxmk to $GOPATH/bin, which will allow you run it directly from a shell.</description></item></channel></rss>