<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>base on rbxmk</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/</link><description>Recent content in base on rbxmk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2022 Anaminus</copyright><atom:link href="https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>math</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/math/</guid><description>The math library contains common mathematical functions and variables.
Overview # Item Kind Description huge Field The value &amp;gt;= any other numerical value. pi Field The value of π. abs Function Returns the absolute value of x. acos Function Returns the arc cosine of x. asin Function Returns the arc sine of x. atan Function Returns the arc tangent of x. atan2 Function Returns the arc tangent of y/ x. ceil Function Returns the smallest integer &amp;gt;= x.</description></item><item><title>os</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/os/</guid><description>The os library contains functions related to the operating system.
Overview # Item Kind Description clock Function Returns the CPU time. date Function Returns the current time. Returns the time as a table. Returns the time as a formatted string. difftime Function Returns the difference between two times. time Function Returns a numeric time. Functions # clock # os.clock(): number
The clock function returns, approximately, the seconds of CPU time used by the program.</description></item><item><title>string</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/string/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/string/</guid><description>The string library provides functions for string manipulation.
All strings have a metatable with the __index field set to this library. This allows functions to be called as methods on strings:
s:byte(...) -- Equivalent to: string.byte(s, ...) Overview # Item Kind Description byte Function Gets the bytes of a string subset. char Function Converts bytes to a string. find Function Finds the indices of a pattern. format Function Formats values as a string.</description></item><item><title>table</title><link>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anaminus.github.io/RBXMK_DOC_TEMPORARY_DO_NOT_USE_OR_YOU_WILL_BE_FIRED/api/libraries/base/table/</guid><description>The table library provides functions for manipulating tables.
Most functions assume that the table is an array, where &amp;ldquo;length&amp;rdquo; refers to the result of the # operator.
Overview # Item Kind Description concat Function Concatenates each element as a string. insert Function Inserts an element. Appends an element. maxn Function Returns the largest positive numerical index. remove Function Removes an element. sort Function Sorts elements. Functions # concat # table.concat(t: {string | number}, sep: string?</description></item></channel></rss>